Guide to the Consumer Reports. Colston E. Warne papers, 1910-1995 and undated RL.11784
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports. Colston E. Warne papers
1910-1995 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Consumer Reports (Firm)
RL.11784
60.0 Linear Feet
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Colston E. Warne was an economist and consumer advocate who served as the first President of Consumers Union from its formation in 1936 until his retirement in 1980. The Consumer Reports Colston E. Warne papers include correspondence, clippings, photographs, scrapbooks, manuscripts and texts of articles and speeches, reports and other printed materials. Correspondents include Arthur Kallet, Dexter Masters, E. Scott Maynes, Edward Reich, James Mendenhall, James Morgan, Jean Whitehall, Leland Gordon, Morris Kaplan, Persia Campbell, Rhoda Karpatkin, Ruby Turner Morris, Walker Sandbach and William Pabst. Institutions represented include the American Council on Consumer Interests, Amherst College, Consumer Federation of America, Cooperative Distributors, Council of Economic Advisors, International Organization of Consumers' Unions (later Consumers International), League for Industrial Democracy, National Consumer Energy Advisory Committee, National Consumers League, National Recovery Administration and the University of Pittsburgh. Topics addressed include academic and intellectual freedom, communism and subversion, consumer and worker education, economics, labor and war-time advertising. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Arrangement
Organized into the following series: Individuals; Organizations; Government; Subjects; General Files; University of Pittsburgh; Amherst College; Consumers Union; Writings, Speeches, Testimonies; Personal Materials; and Additions.
Biographical / Historical
Consumer Reports is a product testing and consumer advocacy nonprofit organization based in Yonkers, N.Y., founded in 1936. Colston E. Warne was an economist and consumer advocate who served as the first President of Consumers Union from its formation in 1936 until his retirement in 1980.
Colston Estey Warne was born in Romulus, New York on 14 August 1900. He grew up in Ithaca, New York and entered Cornell University in 1916. Warne originally planned to become a banker, but later developed a qrowinq interest in labor and social concerns. Warne majored in economics and graduated with a A.B. in 1920 and an M.A. in 1921.
Following a teaching position as an instructor at the University of Pittsburgh, 1921-1922, Warne studied political economics at the University of Chicago. He wrote his dissertation on the consumers' cooperative movement in Illinois. He received his doctorate in 1925.
Warne was an associate professor of economics at the University of Denver, 1925-1926. In 1926 he was appointed to the University of Pittsburgh as an assistant professor of economics. He taught at Pittsburgh until 1930 when he went to Amherst College as an associate professor. He became a full professor in 1942. Dr. Warne taught at Amherst College until his retirement from teaching in 1969.
While at the University of Pittsburgh Dr. Warne became involved in social issue movements such as civil liberties, trade unionism, and the consumer movement. Attracted by the idea of product testing, Dr. Warne became associated with Consumers' Research (the first consumer-product-testing organization) as a member of its advisory board. When workers at Consumers' Research went on strike in 1935, Dr. Warne sided with the strikers. In 1936, some of the strikers and their supporters banded together to form a competitive consumer-product-testing organization, Consumers Union of the United States, Inc. Dr. Warne became Consumers Union's first president.
Under the leadership of Colston Warne, Consumers Union has overcome financial difficulties, subversive charges, and internal disputes to become the world's largest and most influential consumer-product-testing organization. Dr. Warne served as president of Consumers Union until February 1980.
Among his many consumer-related activities, Dr. Warne has served on the Consumer Advisory Committee of the Council of Economics Advisors (1947-1951), the Consumer Advisory Council of the Council of Economic Advisers (1962-1965), the President's Committee on Consumer Interests (1964-1965), the Consumer Advisory Committee of the Commonwealth of Massachusetts (1959-1962), the National Association of Consumers (member of the board of directors, 1947-1956), the Cooperative League of the USA (member of the board of directors, 1926-1929).
Dr. Warne was also affiliated with People's Lobby (president, 1934-1936), the Western Massachusetts Civil Liberties Union (member 1938-1941), the Pittsburgh Branch of the American Civil Liberties Union (chairman, 1927-1930), the Industry, Panels, Wage and Hour Administration, United States Department of Labor (member, 1943-1944), and the United States Coordinator of Fisheries (consultant, 1943).
Largely through Dr. Warne's direction, the International Organization of Consumers' Unions was founded in 1960. Dr. Warne served as I.O.C.U.'s president, 1960-1970, and as treasurer, 1970-1976.
Colston E. Warne died May 20, 1987.
Source: Linda J. Long, Consumers Union Archives revised finding aid, 1989.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Consumer Reports. Colston E. Warne papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2019.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
Advertising Council records
Consumer Reports Archives records
Consumer Reports Arthur Kallet papers
J. Walter Thompson Company. Howard Henderson papers
Jean Kilbourne papers
Collection Overview
The Consumer Reports Colston E. Warne papers include correspondence, clippings, photographs, scrapbooks, manuscripts and texts of articles and speeches, reports and other printed materials. Correspondents include Arthur Kallet, Dexter Masters, E. Scott Maynes, Edward Reich, James Mendenhall, James Morgan, Jean Whitehall, Leland Gordon, Morris Kaplan, Persia Campbell, Rhoda Karpatkin, Ruby Turner Morris, Walker Sandbach and William Pabst. Institutions represented include the American Council on Consumer Interests, Amherst College, Consumer Federation of America, Cooperative Distributors, Council of Economic Advisors, International Organization of Consumers' Unions (later Consumers International), League for Industrial Democracy, National Consumer Energy Advisory Committee, National Consumers League, National Recovery Administration and the University of Pittsburgh. Topics addressed include academic and intellectual freedom, communism and subversion, consumer and worker education, economics, labor and war-time advertising. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Consumer advocacy; consumer protection; Academic freedom; Consumer education; Labor -- United States; World War, 1939-1945; Communism -- United States -- History -- 20th century; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History; Warne, Colston E. (Colston Estey), 1900-1987; Campbell, Persia; University of Pittsburgh. Dept. of Economics
- Individuals, 1921-1981; 1
  - Aaron, Harold, 1942-1979 (Box 1)
  - Ashey, Michael, 1945-1947 (Box 1)
  - Agnew, Paul, 1937-1940 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Eleanor, 1939-1950 (Box 1)
  - Anderson, Kurt, 1930-1975 (Box 1)
  - Andrews, Benjamin, 1940-1961 (Box 1)
  - Arnold, Leslie, 1935-1961 (Box 1)
  - Atwater, Thomas, 1952-1960 (Box 1)
  - Austin, H. Verne, 1958-1970 (Box 1)
  - Ayres, Ruth, 1942, 1952 (Box 1)
  - Banzhaf, John III, 1970-1974 (Box 1)
  - Barghorn, Fred, 1934-1937 (Box 1)
  - Barrett, Stephen, 1973-1976 (Box 1)
  - Beckhart, B. Haggott, 1926-1975 (Box 1)
  - Beebe, Leslie, 1950-1951 (Box 1)
  - Beem, Eugene, 1949-1966 (Box 1)
  - Been, Vicki, 1979 (Box 1)
  - Berberian, John, 1972-1978 (Box 1)
  - Bergsten, C. Fred, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Berliner, David, 1978-1980 (Box 1)
  - Bivens, Gordon E., 1960-1981 (Box 1)
  - Bilkey, Warren, 1952-1960 (Box 1)
  - Black, Kate Leers, 1936-1938 (Box 1)
  - Bonner, Raymond, 1977-1980 (Box 1)
  - Braddicks, Eleanor, 1967-1981 (Box 1)
  - Braden, Joan, 1976 (Box 1)
  - Bradley, Phillips, 1931-1938 (Box 1)
  - Brady, Mildred Edie and Robert, 1939-1973; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Brady report, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Brady, Mildred Edie, 1960-1980 (Box 2)
  - Branch, Mary Sydney, 1940-1943 (Box 2)
  - Braren, Warren, 1971-1980 (Box 2)
  - Brecher, Edward, 1950-1979 (Box 2)
  - Brophy, John, 1928-1936 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Emily, 1931-1956 (Box 2)
  - Brown, Susan Jenkins, 1935-1944 (Box 2)
  - Brunn, George, 1966-1980 (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Persia, 1939-1968; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Campbell, Persia, 1969-1974; 2 folders (Box 2a)
  - Canoyer, Helen, 1941-1961 (Box 3)
  - Carberry, Elizabeth, 1951-1980 (Box 3)
  - Carson, John, 1938-1957 (Box 3)
  - Carstens, Art, 1951-1974 (Box 3)
  - Cassels, John, 1938-1970 (Box 3)
  - Chalmers, William, 1927-1966 (Box 3)
  - Chase, Stuart, 1941-1975 (Box 3)
  - Clark, Lincoln, 1940-1953, 1967 (Box 3)
  - Coit, Eleanor, 1954-1961 (Box 3)
  - Colby, William, 1953-1970 (Box 3)
  - Cole, Charles, 1938-1960 (Box 3)
  - Coombs, Philip, 1952-1964 (Box 3)
  - Crooks, Lawrence, 1938-1970 (Box 3)
  - Crosby, Alexander, 1938-1971 (Box 3)
  - Cross, Hartley, 1933-1948 (Box 3)
  - Cross,Richard, 1974-1981 (Box 3)
  - Dale, Ernst, 1943 (Box 4)
  - Dameron, Kenneth, 1939-1958 (Box 4)
  - Davis, Horace, 1930-1967 (Box 4)
  - Davis, Jerome, 1935-1968 (Box 4)
  - Davis, Loda Mae, 1940-1943 (Box 4)
  - Denenberg, Herbert, 1972-1976 (Box 4)
  - Dickenson, Z.E., 1941-1951 (Box 4)
  - Dickson, Mary, 1932 (Box 4)
  - Dinwiddie, Donal, 1965-1980 (Box 4)
  - Ditlow, Clarence, 1973-1980 (Box 4)
  - Doggett, Lloyd (Box 4)
  - Doskow, Ambrose, 1961-1971 (Box 4)
  - Douglas, Dorothy, 1934-1968 (Box 4)
  - Douglas, Paul H., 1924-1963 (Box 4)
  - East, Marjorie, 1952-1975 (Box 4a)
  - Edmonston, L. Philip, 1978-1981 (Box 4a)
  - Epstein, Samuel S., 1973-1981 (Box 4a)
  - Ferber, John, 1952-1976 (Box 4a)
  - Fleisher, Henry, 1935-1976 (Box 4a)
  - Florman, Monte, 1971-1980 (Box 4a)
  - Ford, Judith, 1978-1981 (Box 4a)
  - Fox, Jean Ann, 1977-1980 (Box 4a)
  - Freedman, Joel, 1956-1968 (Box 4a)
  - Frese, Robert, 1959-1963 (Box 4a)
  - Fuller, Robert, 1943 (Box 4a)
  - Furman, Ira, 1970-1977 (Box 4a)
  - Furness, Betty, 1967-1980 (Box 4a)
  - Galbraith, J. Kenneth, 1943-1967, 1973 (Box 5)
  - Gamble, Philip, 1938-1948, 1953-1976 (Box 5)
  - Garnsey, Morris, 1945-1946, 1953-1967 (Box 5)
  - Gillmor, Daniel, 1965 (Box 5)
  - Givens, Meredith, 1930-1935, 1957-1958 (Box 5)
  - Goldberg, Paul, 1964-1974 (Box 5)
  - Goldstein, E. Ernest, 1946-1967 (Box 5)
  - Goodman, Alan, 1973-1979 (Box 5)
  - Goodman, Dorothy, 1955-1962 (Box 5)
  - Gordon, Leland, 1940-1966; 5 folders (Box 5)
  - Gordon, Leland, 1967-1981; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Goss, George, 1952-1968 (Box 6)
  - Grundfest, Harry, 1943-1950 (Box 6)
  - Guest, James, 1977-1981 (Box 6)
  - Gundlach, Ralph, 1942-1978 (Box 6)
  - Hall, Helen, 1942-1974 (Box 6)
  - Haller, William, 1936-1971 (Box 6)
  - Hanc, John, 1965 (Box 6)
  - Harap, Harry, 1935-1975 (Box 6)
  - Harlow, Ralph, 1932-1943, 1953-1958 (Box 7)
  - Harper, Helen, 1925-1926 (Box 7)
  - Harris, Lement, 1931-1938, 1955-1967 (Box 7)
  - Harris, Robert, 1976-1981 (Box 7)
  - Hayakawa, S.I., 1949-1963 (Box 7)
  - Hellerstein, Jerome, 1932-1980; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Herrman, Robert, 1971-1979 (Box 7)
  - Hertzberg, Sidney, 1964-1965 (Box 7)
  - Hewes, Amy, 1932-1945, 1953-1960 (Box 7)
  - Hoffman, George, 1960-1961, 1975 (Box 7)
  - Hope, John, 1940-1963 (Box 7)
  - Houdelette, Harriot Ahlers, 1931-1939 (Box 7)
  - Isserman, Abraham, 1941-1974 (Box 7)
  - Johnson, Edna DeCoursey, 1973-1979 (Box 7)
  - Jordan, Lynn, 1975-1979 (Box 7)
  - Kallet, Arthur, 1935-1949; 2 folders (Box 7)
  - Kallet, Arthur, 1950-1960; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Kaplan, Morris, 1950-1971; 2 folders (Box 8)
  - Karpatkin, Marvin M., 1967-1975 (Box 8)
  - Karpatkin, Rhoda H., 1961-1976; 3 folders (Box 8)
  - Karpatkin, Rhoda H., 1977-1981; 2 folders (Box 8a)
  - Karpatkin, Rhoda H., 1979-1981 (Box 8a)
  - Kendall, David, 1958 (Box 8a)
  - Kern, Paul, 1937-1972 (Box 8a)
  - Klein, Robert, 1965-1972 (Box 8a)
  - Knoll, Robert, 1964-1981 (Box 8a)
  - Krughoff, Robert M., 1973-1979 (Box 8a)
  - LaFollette, Bronson, 1968-1977 (Box 8a)
  - Laidler, Harry, 1945-1952 (Box 8a)
  - Landau, Irwin, 1973-1978 (Box 8a)
  - Lane, Sylvia, 1955-1959, 1973-1977 (Box 8a)
  - Larrabee, C.B., 1943-1959, 1961 (Box 8a)
  - Lathrop, Milo and Helen Sorenson, 1941-1975 (Box 8a)
  - Lebrun, Harvey, 1943-1944 (Box 8a)
  - Lee, Stewart, 1957-1969 (Box 8a)
  - Lee, Stewart, 1970-1980 (Box 9)
  - Leff, Jonathan, 1960-1981 (Box 9)
  - Lever, E.J., 1942-1967 (Box 9)
  - Lumpkin, Katherine, 1932-1948, 1953-1961 (Box 9)
  - Lushbough, Channing, 1973-1974, 1979 (Box 9)
  - Lynd, Robert, 1942-1945 (Box 9)
  - Margolis, Sidney, 1942-1973 (Box 9)
  - Marlies, Charles, 1939 (Box 9)
  - Marsh, Benjamin, 1937-1951 (Box 9)
  - Mason, Florence, 1943-1960 (Box 9)
  - Mason, Florence, 1960-1961 (Box 9a)
  - Masters, Dexter, 1937-1979; 6 folders (Box 9a)
  - MacColl, William, 1954, 1957 (Box 10)
  - Maynes, E. Scott, 1947-1981; 3 folders (Box 10)
  - McEwen, R.J., 1957-1968 (Box 10)
  - Mendenhall, James, 1942-1969; 5 folders (Box 10a)
  - Michelson, Irving, 1977-1980 (Box 10a)
  - Miller, Clyde, 1937-1961 (Box 10a)
  - Miller, Spencer, 1935-1951, 1954 (Box 10a)
  - Minus, Marian, 1964-1965 (Box 10a)
  - Mitchell, Broadus, 1938-1950, 1957 (Box 10a)
  - Montgomery, Donald, 1938-1948, 1953 (Box 10a)
  - Montgomery, Royal, 1925-1937, 1943, 1959 (Box 10a)
  - Morgan, James, 1954-1980; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Morris, Ruby Turner, 1951-1981; 3 folders (Box 11)
  - Morrow, Dorace, 1935-1939, 1951 (Box 12)
  - Morse, Richard L.D., 1951-1981; 2 folders (Box 12)
  - Myers, Samuel L., 1959-1965 (Box 12)
  - Myerson, Bess, 1969-1973 (Box 12)
  - Nader, Ralph, 1967-1975, 1980 (Box 12)
  - Nagel, Karl, 1973 (Box 12)
  - Nelson, Helen, 1959-1971 (Box 12)
  - Nelson, Helen, 1972-1979 (Box 13)
  - Newman, Joyce, 1977 (Box 13)
  - Nobel, Joel, 1976-1980 (Box 13)
  - Nunn, William, 1928-1944, 1970-1978 (Box 13)
  - O'Connell, Jeffrey, 1966-1977 (Box 13)
  - Outland, George, 1950-1960 (Box 13)
  - Pabst, William, 1935-1968; 3 folders (Box 13)
  - Palmer, Dewey, 1935-1967 (Box 14)
  - Palmer, Frank, 1926-1946, 1951-1975 (Box 14)
  - Pertschuk, Michael, 1975-1977 (Box 14)
  - Peterson, Esther, 1936-1981 (Box 14)
  - Peterson, Oliver, 1935-1951 (Box 14)
  - Pollet, Michael, 1974-1980 (Box 14)
  - Pollock, Frank, 1968-1972 (Box 14)
  - Pooler, Rosemary, 1978-1980 (Box 14)
  - Posin, Dan, 1968 (Box 14)
  - Price, Ray, 1940-1977; 2 folders (Box 14)
  - Raushenbush, Carl, 1935-1939 (Box 15)
  - Raushenbush, Esther, 1943-1954, 1968 (Box 15)
  - Reeves, Albert, 1953-1967; 2 folders (Box 15)
  - Reich, Edward, 1939-1979; 3 folders (Box 15)
  - Reis, Bernard, 1938-1961 (Box 15)
  - Reuter, Richard, 1948-1962 (Box 15)
  - Rosenthal, Benjamin S., 1966-1969, 1972 (Box 15)
  - Ross, Madeline, 1936-1957 (Box 15)
  - Sandbach, Walker, 1964-1970; 8 folders (Box 16)
  - Sandbach, Walker, 1971-0975; 7 folders (Box 17)
  - Sassaman, W.R., 1937-1947 (Box 17)
  - Schoenfeld, David, 1969-1976 (Box 17)
  - Schon, Donald, 1973 (Box 17)
  - Schulkind, Adelaide, 1931-1968 (Box 17)
  - Seligman, Eustace, 1935-1961 (Box 17)
  - Shainwald, Sidney, 1960-1970, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Shainwald, Sybil, 1970-1972 (Box 18)
  - Shearer, Gail, 1974-1976 (Box 18)
  - Smith, Robert L., 1938-1971; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Smith, Wendell R., 1971 (Box 18)
  - Smith, Wray, 1961-1964 (Box 18)
  - Steele, Dorothy, 1944-1964 (Box 18)
  - Strong, Lydia Altschuler, 1937-1966; 2 folders (Box 18)
  - Struglia, Erasmus (Ray), 1957-1975, 1979 (Box 18)
  - Sullivan, Patrick L., 1962-1979 (Box 18a)
  - Swankin, David, 1965-1966, 1968-1974 (Box 18a)
  - Taylor, George, 1938-1946, 1952-1968 (Box 18a)
  - Tead, Ordway, 1932-1938, 1953-1955 (Box 18a)
  - Thorelli, Hans, 1965-1979; 3 folders (Box 18a)
  - Thorp, Willard, 1930 1944, 1952 1960 (Box 19)
  - Troelstrup, Arch, 1952-1980; 4 folders (Box 19)
  - Villard, Henry, 1966-1973 (Box 19)
  - Vogel, Eugele L., 1973-1979 (Box 19)
  - Walsh, Dorothy, 1950-1964 (Box 19)
  - Walter, Diana, 1980 (Box 19)
  - Warbasse, James p., 1931-1959 (Box 19)
  - Ware, Caroline, 1940-1981 (Box 19)
  - Ware, Norman, 1934-1957 (Box 20)
  - Warner, Florence, 1942 1952 (Box 20)
  - Watson, Goodwin, 1937 1949 (Box 20)
  - Weir, Marion, 1942 1961 (Box 20)
  - Weiss, Harry, 1935-1951, 1962 (Box 20)
  - Wendt, Gerald, 1942 1951 (Box 20)
  - Whittaker, Judy, 1977 1980 (Box 20)
  - Whitehill, Jean, 1946-1961; 4 folders (Box 20)
  - Wilcox, Clair, 1939-1969 (Box 20)
  - Wilhelms, Fred, 1943-1960 (Box 20)
  - Williams, C. Arthur, 1972-1975 (Box 20)
  - Williams, Constance, 1935-1959 (Box 20)
  - Williams, Stillman, 1943 (Box 20)
  - Wilson, Dean, 1960-1976 (Box 20)
  - Woltman, Fred, 1930-1936 (Box 20)
  - Woodcock, Leslie, 1934-1941, 1956-1959 (Box 20)
  - Woodruff, Ruth, 1940-1941 (Box 20)
  - Zeuch, William, 1921-1946 (Box 20)
- Organizations, 1924-1981 and undated; 2
  - General, 1924-1981 and undated; 1
    - Advertising Age, 1954-1971 (Box 21)
    - Advertising Club of Springfield, 1941-1943 (Box 21)
    - Affiliated Schools for Workers, 1927-1946; 3 folders (Box 21)
    - American Association for Social Security, 1931-1944 (Box 21)
    - American Association of University Professors, 1935- (Box 21)
    - American Association of University Women, 1931-1960 (Box 21)
    - American Civil Liberties Union, 1928-1972 (Box 21)
    - American Council on Consumer Interests, 1954-1957 (Box 21)
    - American Council on Consumer Interests, 1958-1979; 4 folders (Box 22)
    - American Economic Association, 1961-1968 (Box 22)
    - American Economic Foundation, 1941-1942 (Box 22)
    - American Federation of Labor, 1935-1954 (Box 22)
    - AFL-CIO, 1956-1967 (Box 22)
    - American Federation of Teachers, 1931-1941 (Box 22)
    - American Friends Service Committee, 1948-1967 (Box 22)
    - American Investors Union, 1938-1946 (Box 22)
    - American League Against War and Fascism, 1932-1937 (Box 22)
    - American League for Peace and Democracy, 1938-1941 (Box 23)
    - American Marketing Association, 1953-1973 (Box 23)
    - Association for Evolutionary Economics, 1965-1979 (Box 23)
    - Association of University Teachers, 1932 (Box 23)
    - Better Business Bureau, undated; 2 folders (Box 23)
    - Boston Consumer Cooperative Association, 1935-1936 (Box 23)
    - Brookings Institute, 1930-1936 (Box 23)
    - Brookwood Labor College, 1927-1937 (Box 23)
    - Center for Auto Safety, 1969-1974 (Box 23)
    - Central States Cooperative League, 1924-1936 (Box 23)
    - Citizens Union of Massachusetts, 1941-1942 (Box 23)
    - Civil Liberties Union of Masssachusetts, 1931-1976 (Box 23)
    - Civil Liberties Union of Pennsylvania, 1931-1932 (Box 23)
    - Civil Liberties Union of Philadelphia, 1929 (Box 23)
    - Civil Liberties Union of Pittsburgh, undated (Box 23)
    - Civil Liberties Union of Southern California, 1947 (Box 23)
    - Columbia Conserve Company, 1930-1933 (Box 23)
    - Committee for Research on Consumer Attitudes and Behavior, 1952-1955 (Box 23)
    - Committee on the University Extension of the Connecticut Valley College, 1932-1951 (Box 23)
    - Consumer Assembly, 1965-1967 (Box 24)
    - Consumer Clearing House, 1943-1968 (Box 24)
    - Consumer Education Association, 1939-1940 (Box 24)
    - Consumer-Farmer Milk Cooperative, 1940-1945 (Box 24)
    - Consumer Federation of America, 1967-1979; 6 folders (Box 24)
    - Consumer Federation of America--Distinguished Public Service Award, 1971 (Oversize-folder 1)
    - Consumers' Research, 1928-1981 (Box 24)
    - Cooperative Book Club, 1938 (Box 24)
    - Cooperative Distributors, 1932-1944; 3 folders (Box 25)
    - Cooperative League, 1925-1934 (Box 25)
    - Cooperative League, 1935-1977; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Council of Better Business Bureaus, 1970-1973 (Box 26)
    - Council of National Organizations, 1956-1958 (Box 26)
    - Denver Cooperative, 1926-1927 (Box 26)
    - Eastern States Cooperative League, 1930-1948 (Box 26)
    - Highlander Research and Educational Center, 1940-1969; 2 folders (Box 26)
    - Institute for Consumer Education, 1938-1941 (Box 26)
    - Institute for Labor Studies, 1935-1941 (Box 26)
    - Institute for Propaganda Analysis, 1937 (Box 26)
    - Institutional Research Council, 1962-1963 (Box 26)
    - International Ladies' Garment Workers Union, 1932-1959 (Box 26)
    - International Organization of Consumer Unions (IOCU), 1956-1965; 9 folders (Box 27)
    - International Organization of Consumer Unions (IOCU), 1965-1968; 8 folders (Box 28)
    - International Organization of Consumer Unions (IOCU), 1968-1970; 9 folders (Box 29)
    - International Organization of Consumer Unions (IOCU), 1970-1972; 7 folders (Box 30)
    - International Organization of Consumer Unions (IOCU), 1972-1973; 4 folders (Box 31)
    - International Organization of Consumer Unions (IOCU), 1973-1975; 6 folders (Box 32)
    - International Organization of Consumer Unions (IOCU), 1976-1977; 6 folders (Box 33)
    - International Organization of Consumer Unions (IOCU), 1977-1978; 5 folders (Box 34)
    - International Organization of Consumer Unions (IOCU), 1979-1982; 2 folders (Box 34a)
    - International Organization of Consumer Unions (IOCU)--Reports from Florence Mason to Colston Warne, 1961-1968; 2 folders (Box 34a)
    - Joint Council on Economic Education, 1954-1966 (Box 35)
    - Labor Research Association, 1928-1938 (Box 35)
    - Lawyers Defense Committee, 1950 (Box 35)
    - League for Independent Political Action, 1929-1935 (Box 35)
    - League for Industrial Democracy, 1937-1964; 2 folders (Box 35)
    - League for Mutual Aid, 1930-1969 (Box 35)
    - League of Women Shoppers, 1938-1939 (Box 35)
    - League of Women Voters, 1942 (Box 35)
    - National Association of Consumers, 1948-1963 (Box 35)
    - National Better Business Bureau, 1943-1968 (Box 35)
    - National Bureau of Economic Research, 1954-1965 (Box 35)
    - National Consumer Congress, 1973-1975 (Box 35)
    - National Consumers League, 1928-1962 (Box 35)
    - National Consumers League, 1963-1979 (Box 36)
    - National Council of the Arts, Sciences, and the Professions, 1946-1951 (Box 36)
    - National Council of the Churches of Christ, 1940-1963 (Box 36)
    - National Foundation for Consumer Credit, 1968 (Box 36)
    - National Religion and Labor Foundation, 1935-1952 (Box 36)
    - People's Lobby, 1932-1950; 2 folders (Box 36)
    - Printers' Ink, 1939-1964 (Box 36)
    - Socialist Party, 1931-1943 (Box 36)
    - Survey Research Center, 1952-1953 (Box 36)
    - Teachers Union, 1940-1950 (Box 36)
    - Textile Workers of America, 1939-1944 (Box 36)
    - Washington Center for the Study of Services, 1973-1976 (Box 36)
    - Wellesley Summer Institute, 1935-1950 (Box 36)
    - Wesleyan University, 1937-1942 (Box 37)
    - Workers Education Bureau of America, 1926-1937 (Box 37)
    - YMCA, 1925-1934 (Box 37)
    - YWCA, 1927-1967 (Box 37)
  - International, 1939-1981; 2
    - Afghanistan, 1969 (Box 38)
    - Argentina, 1941-1969 (Box 38)
    - Australia, 1937-1979; 5 folders (Box 38)
    - Austria, 1966-1968 (Box 38)
    - Barbados, 1968-19790 (Box 38)
    - Belgium, 1952-1977 (Box 38)
    - Brazil, 1962-1975 (Box 39)
    - Canada, 1958-1980; 4 folders (Box 39)
    - Central America, 1975-1976 (Box 39)
    - Chile, 1968-1975 (Box 39)
    - China, 1969-1980 (Box 39)
    - Colombia, 1966-1968 (Box 39)